Prangan Ghosh

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

□ pranganghosh7@gmail.com □ +91 8383007824 ♀ Gurgaon, INDIA

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/prangan-ghosh/

OBJECTIVE

A motivated System Development Analyst with 1.5 years of experience in React JS, .Net Core, and SQL Server and eager to acquire new skills. Proven ability to work dedicatedly as a full-stack developer and contribute to the company's objective.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, C#, HTML, CSS, .NET ASP CORE,

Tools and Framework: React, Node.js, Angular, Microsoft SQL Server

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Cargo Flash Info Tech. Jan 2022 - Present Roles and Resposibility

- My experience lies in the fields of full-stack development, including React and JavaScript.
- It is my responsibility to create cross-platform applications such as cargo reservation systems, dashboards, and cargo tracking systems by using React or Angular in addition to .net, Microsoft SQL, and C#.
- As a full-stack developer with expertise in React and JavaScript, I bring a comprehensive skill set encompassing both frontend and backend development.

Intern

Cargo Flash Info Tech. *May 2021 - Jan 2022* Roles and Resposibility

- Working Experience & Extensive knowledge in Python with libraries Such as Sklearn, Numpy, Pandas, EDA.
- Built and Trained the model using Random Forest algorithm and XGBoost classification. Analysed model prediction accuracy using Classification Reports, Confusion Matrix, AUC scores.
- Used python libraries for Web Scraping: Selenium, Beautiful Soup.

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Developer

Oracle India Nov 2019 - Dec 2020

Roles ans Responsibility

- The transformation of technology infrastructure to the cloud with OCI training.
- To match the performance, control, and governance of enterprise datacenters, while delivering the scale, elasticity, and cost-savings of public clouds

PROJECTS

Target Planning System - CRUD and Dynamic Pricing module using React, JS, SQL Server

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

The CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) module is a fundamental component in software development that provides basic operations for managing data within a system.

Airline Revenue Management System using React JS, .NET Core 3.1, SQL Server.

Aug 2022 - Oct 2022

This HS code has a serial batch number called an HS code, followed by a description of goods, and it will display all of the data, whether it is active or not.

OctoGo Reservation System, Crud Form for User Details

May 2022 - Aug 2022

The OctoGo Reservation Form for User Details is an Angular-based component that allows users to enter their personal information for making reservations. It provides a user-friendly and intuitive interface for capturing and validating user data, ensuring a smooth and efficient reservation process

POC - Hazmat Detection using Open CV , Python

Dec 2021 - Mar 2022

Primary Goal: The project focuses on developing a system for HAZMAT (Hazardous Materials) sticker detection using OpenCV (Open Source Computer Vision Library). The objective is to automatically identify and locate HAZMAT stickers on objects or packages, aiding in safety measures and regulatory compliance.

Flipkart Web Scrapping for Refridgerator

Oct 2021 - Nov 2021

Primary Goal: To scrap and analyze the best suitable product for user In PowerBI using ML models

Solution: Data for - 833 Refridgerators was collected from Extracting the Flipkart website. The data is converted into excel and then EDA and Seaborn are performed in python. Four machine learning algorithms were used to predict the accuracy. It is then represented in PowerBI.

EDUCATION

B-Tech in Computer Science Engineering

Manav Rachna International Institute of Research and Studies (MRIIRS) Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

Secondary School

Sherwood Convent School Jun 2016 - Jun 2017

LANGUAGES

| English | Hindi | |
|---------|--------|--|
| Spanish | French | |